C

SUBHAM **JAIN**

Shubham.rapariya2@gmail.com Gurugram, Haryana, India (122004) ☑☑

Frontend Developer

LinkedIn Portfolio Github

SUMMARY

As a detail-oriented front-end developer, strong problem-solving and logical reasoning skills are brought to the table. Proficiency in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and ReactJS, coupled with experience in real-time data fetching using Restful APIs and the implementation of reusable components, mark my expertise. Intensive upskilling in Front-end Development solidifies the candidacy for any front-end developer role.

EDUCATION

GLA University | Mathura 8.4 CGPA

Bachelor of Computer Applications 2014 – 2017

SKILLS

- **Programming Concepts:** HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Java, JSON, JSX
- Frameworks/Libraries: React.js, Bootstrap, Redux Toolkit, Material UI
- **Tools:** Github, Git, Visual Studio Code, Vercel
- Concepts: Agile/Scrum Methodologies, Responsive Web Design, Test Driven Development
- **Soft Skills:** Problem-solving, Teamwork, and Leadership

CERTIFICATIONS

Certification from Meta

- Introduction to Front-End Development
- React Basics
- Programming with JavaScript
- Version Control
- HTML and CSS in depth

Certification from TCS

- Develop Soft Skills that Industry Demands
- Learn Corporate Etiquette

Certification from Atlassian

• Agile with Atlassian Jira

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Achieved All India Rank 98 in NIT MCA Common Entrance Test -2017.
- Graduated with Honors in Bachelor of Computer Applications (BCA).
- Solved 1000+ Questions on the Acciojob Portal.

EXPERIENCE

React Developer

BlackBeltHelp | Feb 2024 - Present

- Collaborate with UX/UI designers to enhance chatbot user experience.
- Integrate chatbots with various platforms and backend systems.
- Continuously improve chatbot understanding and responses
- Address and rectify any issues or bugs in the chatbot's functioning.

Web Developer

Kamakhya Infocom Llp | Jan 2022 - Jan 2024

- Designing and developing new features and functions
- Ensured the functionality of web applications by adeptly employing HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React.
- Troubleshooting problems with performance or user experience
- Translating client requirements into technical specifications.

Web Developer

Risovation | Dec 2020 - Jan 2022

- Tailored and crafted UI to meet specific client needs.
- Ensured website functionality through skilled use of HTML, CSS, JavaScript & React.
- Translating client requirements into technical specifications.

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Full Stack Developer Training

Acciojob | Gurugram | 2023 - Present

- Intensive Upskilling with an average of 97% in Front-end Development.
- Participated in over 20+ Contests and secured an average of 96%.
- Build 10+ projects with advanced Concepts of Web Development

PROJECTS

Crypto Tracker (React)

 Crypto Tracker is a tracker that lets users compare different cryptocurrencies and look at their graphs - prices, total volumes, market cap, etc.

My Portfolio (React)

 Composed a modular structure using React's component-based architecture, enhancing code maintainability and scalability.

YouTube Clone (React)

- Real-time data fetching with YouTube RestfulAPI.
- Modular Architecture: Implemented reusable components clean code, and maintainable code.